Jackie Sweet

eikcaj.sweet@gmail.com • +1 (339) 293-2042

https://github.com/eikkaj • https://www.linkedin.com/in/jackiealdama/ • https://eikkaj.github.io/

Summary Statement

I am a software engineer with 15 years of experience, who loves to architect solutions, build relationships, grow standards, improve quality, coach, mentor, lead, and learn. I am most interested in data privacy, confidential computing, system architecture, and am actively pursuing growth in public speaking.

Technical Skills

Expert (★★★★★): Java, Javascript, Node.js, React, Git, Cloud Architecture (AWS - S3, Cloudfront, ECS, EC2, Athena, Quicksight, Lambda, DynamoDB, RDS, Nitro Enclaves), Technical Writing, Object Oriented Design, Digital Asset Management, Enterprise Content Management, API Design, Sequelize, SSO/SCIM, SAML, Test Driven Development, Serverless

Advanced ($\star\star\star\star\star$): Chrome Extension Development, SQL, Content Management Systems, Cloud Security, Confidential Computing, Descope, Okta, Typescript, Terraform, Typescript, Snowflake, Docker, Web Scraping, Microservices Familiar ($\star\star\star\star\star$): Perl, Python, Pulumi, Openshift, Streaming, Kubernetes, RPAs

Work Experience

Senior Software Engineer - Team Lead

CoApp

October 2022-Present

Stack: React, Node, MySQL, DynamoDB, AWS, Nitro Enclave, Chrome extensions, IndexedDB, Windows Desktop Application Development

- I oversee all development, systems, cloud, security, and compliance.
- I introduced and matured software engineering processes including SCRUM, feature/release planning, and technical/functional specification development.
- I have implemented best practices such as Test-Driven Development (**TDD**), Infrastructure as Code (**IAC**), and Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment (**CICD**).
- Regular contributions of feature development in Node (Express, Sequelize, Postgres, MySQL), React (Typescript, Material UI, Styled), Chromium Web Extensions, Serverless Applications (Lambda, SQS, EventBridge, DynamoDB, S3, RDS, Aurora, Quicksight).
- Design and implementation of all devops CICD (GH Actions), Tests, IAC (Terraform).
- Algorithm design for a rule computation engine capable of translating user-built "rules" and data retrieval via API and web scraping tactics, following core mathematical principles in formula execution.
- Speaker representing CoApp at the Confidential Computing Summit 2023 in San Francisco, showcasing our unique and futuristic use-case.

Chief Technology Officer

LittleNewt

October 2021-August 2022

Stack: React, Spring Boot, Python, Serverless, MySQL

• Founding engineer and CTO where I successfully built the initial platform meant to disrupt the US tax industry, aiming to help CPAs and other tax professionals do their jobs more easily and effectively.

Senior Software Engineer

Nuxeo, Professional Services

June 2017 - June 2021

Stack: Java (OSGI), Nuxeo, Polymer, React, Angular, AWS (RDS, SQS, SNS, EC2, ECS, Lambda)

- Senior full-stack, customer-facing software engineer involved in a wide range of projects including: Nuxeo implementations, security analysis, performance analysis, UI customization, custom bulk-ingestion application, training / enablement, advisory, POCs, pre-sales engineering efforts, developer advocacy, and platform development
- Organized company-wide hackathon
- Regularly contributed technical content on the Nuxeo website and across social media platforms

Software Engineer

Propeller Media Works June 2016 - June 2017

Stack: Javascript, PHP, D3, MySQL

- Full stack engineer, primarily working with our custom CMS and wordpress development. Daily work included site maintenance, data analysis, and working on major enhancements for customer sites.
- I successfully rebuilt our interactive trail map engine using d3.

Software Engineer

Nutraclick (Force Factor)

November 2015 - June 2016

Stack: PHP, Javascript, Wordpress, Magento, MySQL, Oracle

Full stack engineer who supported over 20 websites and systems in e-commerce and direct-to-consumer marketing.

Software Engineer

Partners Healthcare

January 2012 - November 2015

Stack: PHP, .NET, JS, MySQL, Oracle, JSF, Seam, EJB3, HTML, CSS

• Lead software engineer for the Partners Biobank with Partners Personalized Medicine.

Education

Bachelor of Science (B.S.) in Computer Science

Boston University

September 2011 - May 2014

- Acceptance into a highly competitive, advanced, full-time computer science program while also working professionally full-time.
- Recipient of multiple scholarships for entry into this program.

Volunteer

Head of Engineering

Farm to Crag

April 2023 - Present

Stack: React, Node, MySQL, AWS, Google Maps API

Leading software engineering efforts for a non-profit focused on bringing sustainable agriculture and rock climbers together